aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Brutal aliens escaped from the Space Prison Sargasso.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들
To protect the Earth from those evil hands, the brave high school students, Dagwon, keep fighting on to this day.
그 마수로부터 지구를 지키기 위해 오늘도 계속해서 싸우는 고등학생 용자 다그온
The result of their further power up is Dag Fire's Strength Fusion, Power Dagwon.
그들의 거듭되는 파워업이 바로 다그 파이어의 강력 합체 파워 다그온인 것이다
En Fights in the Stratosphere
엔, 성층권에서 싸우다
Fortress Alien Pat Seijin
Appears
요새 우주인 패트 성인
등장
Beware of high places.
높은 곳을 조심하라
En's fortune today says for you to beware of high places.
엔의 오늘의 운세는 "높은 곳을 조심하라"
라고 나와있어
Fortune telling? How stupid.
점이냐, 바보같이…
Wh- what's up with that attitude?!
뭐, 뭐냐 그 태도는?
Ms. Maria's kindly fortune telling for you and you're being rude!
모처럼 마리아 씨가 점 봐주신다는데, 실례잖아!
Apologize!
사과해라!
Hey, look!
이것 봐!
This woman is just reading a fortune written on some weird magazine!
이녀석은 정체모를 잡지에 나온 점을 그저 읽을 뿐이잖아!
Your face says it all.
너, 뻔히 보인다구
You're just carpetbagging to Maria!
마리아한테 잘 보이려고 하는 거 말이야
Wh- what?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
Now, Geki's turn.
그럼, 다음은 게키야
Be aware of a loan using documents, stocks, and legal seals.
문서, 증권, 인감 등의 사채 사용에 주의
There are possibilities of causing troubles.
분쟁을 일으킬 우려가 있다
Also, friction between people is expected, and luck slumps.
또, 인간 관계의 대립이 예상되며, 운은 급하락
Both luck and effort of love have end in waste of labor.
애정운도, 노력이 헛수고가 되어 좋지 않은 상황
You should calm down for a while.
당분간 냉각 기간을 가지자
What's the problem?
무슨 일입니까?
My child! My child!
애가… 애가!
What?!
뭐라고?!
Mommy!
엄마~
Alright, let's combine!
좋아, 합체다!
We will stop them!
녀석들의 움직임을 막는다!
Magma Blast!
마그마 블래스트!
Turbo Wheel Cutter!
터보 호일 커터!
Shadow Gun Beam!
섀도우 건 빔!
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
Power Dagwon! What's wrong?
파워 다그온!
왜 그래?!
Damn...! Super Liner Crush!
젠장…!
슈퍼 라이너 크러시!
Shadow Beast King Slash!
섀도우 아왕참!
What the hell is going on?!
대체 뭐야?!
Where are they shooting from?!
어디서 쏴대는 거지?
You're not running away!
놓치지 않는다!
Shadow Dagwon! Super Liner Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온!
You're doing good, Lian! Gunkid!
잘한다, 라이안!
건키드!
Lian! They're shooting from a higher place!
라이안, 아직 더 위에서 쏘고 있어!
You punk! Where are you?!
이놈! 어디 있느냐?!
Gunkid!
건키드!
Lian! Gunkid!
라이안! 건키드!
Damn!
젠장!
This is impossible...
그, 그런 말도 안되는…
How are the repairs going?
수리의 진행 상황은?
It will take more time.
아직 시간이 걸립니다
So will the Shadow Jet.
새도우 제트도 마찬가지야
How are Lian and Gunkid doing?
라이안과 건키드의 상태는 어때?
They are badly injured. They won't be able to move for a while.
중상이야, 당분간 못 움직여
We only have En's Power Dagwon left for now...
현재 전력은 엔의 파워 다그온 뿐인가…
Looks dangerous.
위험한데…
If those robots invade again, then we won't be able to mobilize!
지금 증기 로봇이 쳐들어 오면 어쩔 도리가 없어
No, even if the repairs are done, as long as they attack us with the beam, nothing will change.
아니오, 설사 수리가 끝났다 할지라도 그 빔 공격이 있는 한, 달라질 게 없어요
We'll end up a honeycomb if we approach.
다가가면 벌집이 되어버립니다
Where the heck is it shooting from?!
대체 어디서 쏴대는 거야, 응?!
What can we do?!
그럼 어떡하란 거야?!
Must we wait and see the city being destroyed?!
마을이 엉망이 되는 걸 잠자코 보기만 하란 거냐?!
Calm down, En.
냉정해져라, 엔
They've appeared again!
또 나타났어!
What is Dagwon doing?!
다그온은 뭘 하고 있는 거야?
Knock those guys down!
저런 녀석들, 해치워 달라구!
Are you stupid?! Running away is a priority!
너 바보니?!
얼른 도망쳐야지!
How noisy...
시끄럽구만…
Finish it, Fire Shovel!
해치워, 파이어 셔벨!
Good job!
잘한다!
Fire Shovel!
파이어 셔벨!
How dare you do that to my Fire Shovel?!
이자식…
내 파이어 셔벨을…!
We have a problem!
크, 큰일이야!
It took Fire Stratus with it!
저 안에 파이어 스투라투스가…!
What?!
뭐라고?!
En...
엔…
Fire Shovel is...
파이어 셔벨은…?
Fire Shovel!
파이어 셔벨!
This robot...
이 로봇…
Where is it going?
대체 어디로 가는 거지?
Earth!
지구?!
N- no way!
그, 그런 말도 안되는…!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
I've come to space...
우주에 와 버렸잖아…
That can't be!
말도 안돼!
Hey! Go back to Earth, you idiot!
야! 지구로 돌아가, 멍청아!
Wh-what is that?
뭐, 뭐야, 저건?
Is this their stronghold?!
이, 이게 녀석들의 본거지인가?
Damn...
젠장…
How dare you!
이자식!
I- I see...
그, 그랬구나
They were stealing the iron from Earth to construct this fortress!
이 요새를 건조하기 위해 지구에서 철을 빼앗고 있는 거야
I must destroy it.
부숴버려야 해
If this horrible thing gets completed, the Earth will end up dead!
이런 어처구니없는 물건이 완성되었다간 지구는 터무니없는 결과를 맞이하게 되어버려!
Just you wait.
기다리고 있어라
Was that an alien from Sargasso?
지금 그게 사르갓소의 우주인인가?
What's this sound?
뭐야, 이 소리는?
Elbow Claw!
엘보 클로!
Shoulder Burn!
숄더 번!
Fire Stratus!
파이어 스투라투스!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Let me go, you... you-!
놔라, 요놈아!
It's hot...
뜨거워…
A blast furnace?
용광로인가?
Y-you must be...
네, 네놈은…?
Fire Shovel...
파이어 셔벨…!
Fire Shovel!
파이어 셔벨!
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온
Power Shovel Arm!
파워 셔벨 암!
Power Knee Kick!
파워 니 킥!
Magma Blast!
마그마 블래스트!
Power Burn!
파워 번!
Who are those two just before?
아까 그 두사람은, 대체…?
Power Tank Mode!
파워 탱크 모드!
I see!
그렇군!
This is the heart of the stronghold!
이게 이 요새의 심장부구나!
Alright! I'll show'em!
좋았어! 똑똑히 봐라
Power Burn!
파워 번!
What's going on?
무슨 일이지?
It's En! En did something!
엔이야
엔이 뭔가 한 거라구!
Look, Luna.
봐라, 루나
By the frictional heat of the atmosphere, Power Dagwon is about to meet its end.
대기와의 마찰열로 그 대단한 파워 다그온도 끝장이다
Damn... so hot...
젠장~! 뜨겁다!
Will I...
나는…
나는…!
Will I... die?
죽는 건가?!
What the-?
뭐지?
I-is it saving me?
구, 구해주는 건가?
En!
엔~!
Are you alright?
괜찮나?!
Good job, En.
잘했다, 엔
En. What is this shuttle?
엔, 이 셔틀은?
I don't know.
모르겠어
Who are you?
넌 누구지?
Are you a comrade?
우리 편이냐?
Hey, please wait!
이봐, 기다려!
Who was that guy?
녀석은 대체…
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
-Wait!
-What's wrong, Geki?
-기다려라!
-왜 그래, 게키?
-Get that bastard!
-"That bastard"?
-저녀석 잡아라!
-저녀석?
A sickening brat was riding a motorcycle with a side car!
사이드카가 달린 오토바이에 탄 아니꼽게 생긴 녀석인데 말이야
Ms. Maria is crying because that brat did something to her! Unforgivable!
그녀석에게 나쁜 짓을 당해서 마리아 씨가 울었다구 용서 못해!
It's not the time for that! An UFO of Sabarath Seijin has appeared!
그러고 있을 때가 아니야 사바라스 성인의 UFO가 나타났어!
Wh- what the?! That space shuttle is fighting against that UFO!
이, 이럴수가?! UFO와 싸우고 있는 건 그 스페이스 셔틀이잖아!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Electrostatic Appearance! Dag Thunder
다음회 용자지령 다그온
전격등장 다그 선더
(Rai: 雷; thunder)
The 7th Dagwon's name is Thunder Rai!
일곱 번째 다그온의 이름은 선더 라이!
Electrostatic Appearance! Dag Thunder
전격등장 다그 선더